<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-21T10:19:34+08:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Never Move About</title><subtitle>Talking About Ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title><link href="/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" /><published>2017-07-27T17:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T17:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/the-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-editor">&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &amp;gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T16:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T16:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title><link href="/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" /><published>2017-07-27T15:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T15:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/managing-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="/managing-users">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making your site private</title><link href="/private-sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making your site private" /><published>2017-07-27T14:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T14:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/private-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="/private-sites">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase. You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar. Do remember though, this is not secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title><link href="/advanced-markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" /><published>2017-07-27T13:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T13:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/advanced-markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="/advanced-markdown">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've gotten pretty comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;all the basics&lt;/a&gt; of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor If you've gotten pretty comfortable with all the basics of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown! As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using. Special formatting As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example: strike through highlight *escaped characters* Writing code blocks There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, like this. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks: .my-link { text-decoration: underline; } If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Prism.js. Full bleed images One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a #hash value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example: which is styled with... img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] { max-width: 100vw; } This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles. Reference lists The quick brown fox, jumped over the lazy dog. Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference. Creating footnotes The quick brown fox[1] jumped over the lazy dog[2]. Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post. Full HTML Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example: Foxes are red ↩︎ Dogs are usually not red ↩︎</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting up your own Ghost theme</title><link href="/themes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up your own Ghost theme" /><published>2017-07-27T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/themes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/themes">&lt;p&gt;Creating a totally custom design for your publication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;Ghost Theme Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, or you can simply create your own from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/marketplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like &lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, for example, outputs the name of the current author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TryGhost/Casper&quot;&gt;the source code for Casper&lt;/a&gt;, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;default.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;post.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing a post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing the home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got &lt;a href=&quot;http://themes.ghost.org/docs/about&quot;&gt;full and extensive theme documentation&lt;/a&gt; which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a &lt;strong&gt;#themes&lt;/strong&gt; channel in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.ghost.org&quot;&gt;public Slack community&lt;/a&gt; which we always recommend joining!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Creating a totally custom design for your publication Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code. There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the Ghost Theme Marketplace, or you can simply create your own from scratch. Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like , for example, outputs the name of the current author. The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at the source code for Casper, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together. default.hbs is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template. post.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing a post. index.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing the home page. and so on We've got full and extensive theme documentation which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use. If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a #themes channel in our public Slack community which we always recommend joining!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">About Idea Journal</title><link href="/idea-journal" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About Idea Journal" /><published>2017-06-09T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/idea-journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/idea-journal">&lt;p&gt;我在coursera上的Creative, Innovation and Change这门课上第一次接触到Idea Journal这个概念，我还记得那位老教授说自己已经有好几本Idea Journal，任何有灵感的时候都会记下来，像一个list，反复检查里面的ideas，”好“的灵感可以想办法实现它，“不好”的灵感则慢慢就被淘汰掉。关于要做Idea Journal的想法在之后几年中时不时浮现在脑海里，但是一直没有很好的形式，也没有给自己强大的动力。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人就像一台源源不断生产idea的机器，我想从这方面来说现在的机器还远不如人这台“机器”厉害。以前看过一个说法，灵感是上帝的礼物，碰巧经过你的大脑，所以有人碰到灵感的时候会不顾一切地想要记下来，因为这个礼物停留时间有限，没有被重视的话就会去找下一个幸运的人。我们可以用各种文字或符号的形式记下灵感，音乐家现在倒是可以用语音把想到的音乐片段录下来了。这种说法是有一定道理的，让我们从某种程度上更珍惜灵感的闪现，也更重视灵感的记录和转化。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我有时候和别人进行对话的时候，谈了很久发现竟然聊到了一个和对话开始完全不同的话题，这种有趣的现象让我产生好奇去回溯我们是怎么一步步进行对话的，中间经过了哪几次跳跃，每一次跳跃的联系在哪里。我想，人在&lt;strong&gt;关联性思考（associative thinking）&lt;/strong&gt;方面的能力很强大，话题之间的关联性可以很强大，也可以很微弱，都能够产生话题跳跃的有效性，灵感的产生也可以说是来源于这种associative thinking。我时常在脑子里和自己对话，讨论一些话题，在各种话题交会的过程中产生了一些灵感，这些灵感让我觉得有必要把它们表达出来而不是仅仅让它们出现过，因此灵感的表达也显得重要起来。可以说，人自己本身就是那个带着礼物的上帝，这个礼物产生于大脑进行的关联性思考，记下灵感就是为了唤起自己对思考过程的记忆而努力留下线索（clue）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但是我认为，表达灵感和创造灵感完全不相同。表达是灵感的第二次创造，第一次创造已经发生在大脑中（这是为什么你会“产生”灵感），第二次创造会尽可能模仿或接近第一次创造的活动，但是没有办法复刻一个完全相同的思考活动。第二次创造过程，就是手中拿着那些自己曾经记下的clues，想要把自己脑中曾经走过的路再走一遍，但这条路和当时走过的可能有很多不一样的地方，即使它们的目的地都相同。但是，第一次创造不见得就是完美的，有时候好的作品就是需要不断的打磨，我更看中的是第一次创造中产生的关联性思考活动，那完全是一种自发的（spontaneous）的思考活动，不会强迫自己为了创造而创造，有的关联性非常微弱但仍然不妨碍大脑选择这条狭窄的道路走下去。所以，第一次创造的记录对我来说很重要，因为这种思考活动的价值。而之后的第二次创造，则需要加入自己理性的判断和梳理，使之表达得更充分更合理。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以，我把这个博客叫&lt;em&gt;Idea Journal&lt;/em&gt;的原因就是为了在记下灵感之后，尽早地表达出来，让两次创造活动尽量接近。这需要不断的练习，更刻意（deliverate）的练习。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nini</name></author><category term="creativity" /><summary type="html">我在coursera上的Creative, Innovation and Change这门课上第一次接触到Idea Journal这个概念，我还记得那位老教授说自己已经有好几本Idea Journal，任何有灵感的时候都会记下来，像一个list，反复检查里面的ideas，”好“的灵感可以想办法实现它，“不好”的灵感则慢慢就被淘汰掉。关于要做Idea Journal的想法在之后几年中时不时浮现在脑海里，但是一直没有很好的形式，也没有给自己强大的动力。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">大隐隐于市</title><link href="/be-in-the-city" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="大隐隐于市" /><published>2017-06-02T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/be-in-the-city</id><content type="html" xml:base="/be-in-the-city">&lt;p&gt;经常有人问我：你喜欢在上海生活吗？我的回答一般是：也许吧，我也不知道。有时明明深切地感觉到，自己对生活在这个城市感到非常满意，但不是因为它的繁华，而是因为自己足够渺小。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;今天看了一个Ted Talk讲述内向性格的力量，谈到内向的人需要空间和时间独处，想到高中写的唯一一篇高分作文就是大谈独处之道，但那时的我对独处的认识其实也不是十分清晰。内向和外向不是绝对的泾渭分明，大部分人对自己内向的一面更加敏感，对自己外向的一面经常认为理所当然，所以深入交流到一定程度才有可能告诉别人：其实我有点（很）内向。人需要意识到自己的性格是一个仪表盘，指针在内向与外向之间来回摆动，学习发挥两种性格的力量。外向性格在与他人深入交流、公众场合表达观点、建立情感等方面有很大作用，而内向性格则使你学会与自己相处。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当我一个人的时候，内心比较平静，很少有情绪的大起大落，对周围环境的观察更加敏锐，得到的体会也更加丰富。最近上班的时候明明天气很热，却控制不住自己想要骑车到公司。路上川流不息的车辆，来来往往的路人，从容指挥的交警，还有思想一直开小差的我。幸亏自己没有生活在1984年，否则可能真的因为神情涣散而被判思想罪或者脸罪。对于是否要长久生活在上海，我不是很确定，自己也想生活在一个理想的环境里，但是也许最发达的国家如美国，也有着他们所面临的烦恼。这个世界上也许并不存在所谓“最理想的环境”，就像《Designing Your Life》中所说的不存在”最好的工作“一样，我们应当主动创造一个自己想要的生活，而这样的生活和环境可能没有太大关系。这种主动创造”理想生活“的想法，让我想到古人所说的”小隐隐于林，大隐隐于市“的智慧，在城市中生活也可以做到像隐居者一样，拥有独处的时间，和自己进行对话；保持敏锐的观察力和创造力，激发灵感实现自我表达。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我记得有一天早晨骑车等红绿灯的时候，偶然抬头发现了一道清晰的彩虹，一架飞机穿过，留下长长的尾巴。这次偶然抬头让我和彩虹相遇，说不出当下的感觉多么美好，只是在等的时候忍不住抬头看，不断加深它在我心里的感觉。今天在相同地方等红绿灯时，看到一对老人，老爷爷步履蹒跚，推着老伴儿的轮椅。不知道为什么，虽然他们面容衰老，但是我却有一种感觉是他们对城市的观察可能和我一样敏锐，甚至好奇。我始终对自己生活在城市里能够观察到丰富的画面，感到一阵欣慰。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nini</name></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">经常有人问我：你喜欢在上海生活吗？我的回答一般是：也许吧，我也不知道。有时明明深切地感觉到，自己对生活在这个城市感到非常满意，但不是因为它的繁华，而是因为自己足够渺小。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">想象力是魔鬼吗</title><link href="/is-imagination-evil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="想象力是魔鬼吗" /><published>2017-05-17T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/is-imagination-evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="/is-imagination-evil">&lt;p&gt;最近在读钱钟书的文集《写在人生边上》、《人生边上的边上》，在他的散文中、文学批评中或者外文翻译中，经常读到一些有意思的见解，印象比较深的应该是高中学过的《读&lt;伊索寓言&gt;》，相恨见晚的文章是《谈交友》，其他文章中也会偶尔跳跃出理性的幽默来。只是想来觉得好笑，这本书是七八年前就买的，买回来束之高阁，直到封皮泛了黄。当工作、生活落定之后，强烈地有看书的欲望，才把这本书带了过来。用橡皮擦干净脏了的封皮，一翻开，很多相似的感受跳了出来，很多感受竟然还是来源于最近三个多月的经历，真奇怪。我应该研究一下，这种似曾相识和感同身受到底是一种巧合还是一种心理暗示。不过，也许这就是读书的意义所在，所以什么时候开始读书都不算晚，你和它一直是彼此了解的老朋友。&lt;/伊索寓言&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;就比如说，毕业的时候参加了一个毕业生演讲比赛，我谈到了想象力的重要性，其实想表达的是“形象思维”对工作中创造力的提升，因为这是我自己亲身的体会，无奈时间太短，也就肤皮潦草地谈了谈想象力的好处。这本书快看到结尾的时候，看到钱钟书和杨绛翻译了西方理论家对形象思维的各种观点，从古典理论到现代理论，惊喜之余也要感到庆幸，也许读了那些文章，我就不敢言之凿凿地说想象力是多么多么“伟大”了。刚刚看完一多半关于想象力的古典理论，我认为其中对想象力的观点多半是有些偏颇的，比如：把想象力和理智互为对立，认为知识来源于理智，而“想象是萎褪了的感觉”；把人在身体生病、精神生病、做梦时的幻想当作低级的想象；认为疯子、情人、诗人的想象力最丰富等等。这些古典理论的偏颇可以被理解，因为其中很少从生物学尤其是脑科学的角度去分析，当然也是因为当时的生物学也是古典的吧。所以我对很多观点不太认同，我猜想现代的理论应该会和现代的生物学联系在一起，从而可以从更科学的角度去探讨想象力，如果接下来的文章中没有读到这种观点，也可能是因为最新的研究远在钱钟书的译文之后了。所以没有读完所有的译文，却急着要谈自己的想法，也是为了摆脱其他人的论作对自己观点的影响，我要承认自己的想法容易受到别人的影响，但我认为这是人性使然，也犯不着感到自责。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我在Coursera上《Learning How To Learn》这门课里学习过，当你工作学习很累的时候，熬夜不一定是解决问题的办法，做梦的时候你的大脑也在为你解决问题，所以当你被卡住（get stuck）了，应该睡觉。这也是我上大学以来一直的做法，虽然也有一种说法是：有些人有“熬夜的基因”。可是我仍然认为睡觉、做梦也是一种解决问题的方法，你大脑中的潜意识在运作，做梦时经常产生一种unreasonable的想象，事物之间也有着不可思议的联系，一觉醒来梦的内容也许忘记了（其实大部分都会忘记），但梦带来的“解决方法”却隐约印在了脑子里，也许这就是起床后感受到的新鲜感。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有一天工作的时候，忽然想到了一个问题：人可以凭空创造东西吗？我们讨论一个富有创意的东西，总会说第一个想到这个主意的人真聪明或者真有想象力。那么不禁要问，第一个人到底是怎么想到这个主意的？如果没有任何和其他事物的联系，光凭着想象力可以创造一个完全新鲜的事物吗？又或者说想象力的基础和来源是什么，它的营养来自于哪里？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我深信，事物的创造多来自于发现事物之间的关系，想象力运作的结果是将看起来不相关的事情找到一种联系，有时候也是一种对不相关事物的理解力，《Learnng How To Learn》中提到的chunking也许就是这种理解力产生的过程。要我说，第一个想到好主意的人是第一个发现这种联系的人，这种联系的新鲜感让人觉得富有创意。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;看到那么多理论家对想象力这么感兴趣，可见这种能力的可贵和神秘性。而古典理论家对于想象力的理解，多少也是加入了想象力的，就像我现在，对有关想象力的理论只了解零星的片段，加上自己一些有限的经历，却努力阐述自己对想象力的理解，也是对我的想象力的考验。对想象力的依赖多少是有些危险的，尤其是误把想象当做现实和理智的时候，但想象、现实和理智往往是交融在一起、互相影响的，很难讲清楚应该怎样分辨想象力的误用。也许读完了剩下的译文，心里就会有一个答案吧。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nini</name></author><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html">最近在读钱钟书的文集《写在人生边上》、《人生边上的边上》，在他的散文中、文学批评中或者外文翻译中，经常读到一些有意思的见解，印象比较深的应该是高中学过的《读》，相恨见晚的文章是《谈交友》，其他文章中也会偶尔跳跃出理性的幽默来。只是想来觉得好笑，这本书是七八年前就买的，买回来束之高阁，直到封皮泛了黄。当工作、生活落定之后，强烈地有看书的欲望，才把这本书带了过来。用橡皮擦干净脏了的封皮，一翻开，很多相似的感受跳了出来，很多感受竟然还是来源于最近三个多月的经历，真奇怪。我应该研究一下，这种似曾相识和感同身受到底是一种巧合还是一种心理暗示。不过，也许这就是读书的意义所在，所以什么时候开始读书都不算晚，你和它一直是彼此了解的老朋友。</summary></entry></feed>